groovypost.com 2019-06-26

# Privacy Policy

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.groovypost.com. We are an independent and privately owned publisher in the United States.

## What we do

We publish daily tech news, tips, and reviews. That’s our business and in order to keep the website free vs. paid subscription or a paywall, we show ads to our readers and offer a [free newsletter](https://www.groovypost.com/emailsub/) to keep up-to-date with all our content.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help determine if the comment is legitimate or SPAM. This information is also provided to the service [Akismet](https://akismet.com/privacy/) to check if it’s legitimate or SPAM.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Cookies

Like almost all sites on the internet, we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit my site. Although this will never make me rich, it does allow me to operate the site and keep it free for anyone who is groovy. These third-party companies may use information ( _not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number_ ) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

Almost all websites in the world use Cookies in order to identify your session on their website and enable you to do things like login, personalize your session etc…  If you would like more information about cookies and learn about the choices you have to disable some of the tracking by these companies, [click here](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Another option is to disable cookies in your browser however by doing this you will no longer be able to use most websites. Any questions or comments regarding the privacy policy should be sent to [privacy@groovyPost.com](mailto:privacy@groovyPost.com).

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics and Advertising

GroovyPost users several Google Service for Analytics and Advertising purposes. If you decide to visit our website, please review the [Google Privacy and Terms page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) to fully understand how Google uses information from sites like groovyPost to provide its various services. This page will also explain how to update your Google account to [control how your data is stored](https://myactivity.google.com/) on Google Services, how to export it as well as how to delete it.

## How long we retain your data

### Comments

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

### Other Data

Users who register on our website to either sign up for a Paid subscription or Donation, we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

### Comments

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service called Akismet. This is a standard service used by almost all Websites on the internet. Its [privacy policy can be found here](https://akismet.com/privacy/).

### Other Data

We do not collect, process or store any financial information from our users. Instead, we leverage third parties to process all support subscriptions and donations. In these cases, the information you provide to process your payment will be sent to the payment providers. Below is a link to the privacy policy for the service providers used:

## Your contact information

To see how to contact us directly with questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please visit this our [contact page](https://www.groovypost.com/contact/).

## Additional information

### Newsletter

As a groovyReader or subscriber to my newsletter, you can expect the following in regards to your privacy:

  1. If you sign up for my newsletter, your email address will only be used by my site, groovyPost. If you cancel your free subscription, I will delete your email address immediately from my newsletter system.
  2. I will **never** sell, trade, transfer or give away any information you provide me. **Period. No exceptions!**
  3. I will **never** ask for or collect purposely any [personally identifiable information](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personally_identifiable_information "PII Data") for any reason. In the odd event it’s been collected or left on my site, please [contact me](https://www.groovypost.com/contact/) and I will purge it from the site immediately.
  4. As of May 2018, I use AWeber as the service which delivers my newsletter. The AWeber [Privacy Policy can be found here](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm).
  5. At the bottom of email Newsletter, email is a link to unsubscribe. All data about you will be purged from AWeber 30 days after unsubscribing.

### Affiliate Link Disclosure

Some of the links on groovyPost.com contain affiliate links, which means that if you choose to make a purchase, I will earn a commission. This commission comes at no additional cost to you. Please note, I only recommend quality products from companies I trust. I recommend them because I believe they are either super cool, or I’ve personally used them. Not because of the small commissions I make if you decide to buy something.

### Use of website

Our site, groovyPost.com is free to browse and enjoy. If you are not in agreement with the information we collect and store per the details on this page, please [delete all cookies in your browser](https://www.groovypost.com/?s=delete+cookies) and discontinue visiting our site.

 _Update 5/25/18_
